With the ninth pick in the 2026 NFL
draft, the Cleveland Browns select
Spencer Fono. Tackle Utah in studio.
It's got a nice ring to it, buddy.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Sounds pretty awesome.
>> You were just You were walk You just had
your press conference down there and you
walked in and we've got all of our folks
in the office here and they were pretty
excited to see you. You have an
infectious personality and attitude. You
did a little posing for us for them
which was very exciting. They were
jacked up about What has this been like,
man?
>> It's just been a It's been a dream come
true. I mean, every every part of this
um these last 24 hours has been like a
part of my dream. So, be able to do
this, it's been a blessing. It's been a
blessing.
>> So, we got to see a little clip of the
call and we know the story now that from
the combine you drove here from Indie
and as people who make that drive off
that drive stinks. Terrible.
>> It's one of the worst drives on 70. It's
terrible. You didn't mind it. You were
all excited. What
>> you have that and then he says this time
we're going to get you a plane. A little
bit different transportation this time
to Cleveland. What was uh what was that
whole experience like for you?
>> I I couldn't even tell you about the
drive because it was the same it was the
same story where I just closed my eyes
and I was here.
>> So, you're good at sleeping anyway? I
>> am. That's a great skill.
>> I'm pretty good at sleeping. So, it was
the same thing. The private jet was
really impressive though because I I
can't believe I I promise you I closed
my eyes when we're in the air and I
opened my eyes and we're on the ground
and I thought we were still in Utah.
Like that was it was so strange.
>> There's no better way to fly than that.
>> Yeah, that was awesome.
>> When you uh came over, you were the
first one that we had, right? and you
went straight from combine to here. Um,
what was it about the conversations and
the familiar you had with AB and and
around our guys? Did you have an inkling
that perhaps you'd be a Cleveland Brown?
>> Uh, I feel like I did. I don't know.
Just all the all the conversations that
I had and um the relationships I was
I've I've been starting to make. I feel
like all of it just has felt um really
genuine. It's felt right.
>> Yeah.
when you were going through this process
having the last two years you played
right tackle you played left tackle
obviously your first year freshman
all-American you've been all-American
the last two years you did that you know
accommodate a teammate and do what was
best for your team there by the way two
first round tackles [laughter] on the
Utah youths
>> this is my dog bro just seeing him go to
the Patriots I was screaming at the TV
>> you I love it you give a little has he
been a little rzing about his dancing
>> oh I saw that video too [laughter]
oh my gosh that was hilarious
>> you came in and more just had like a
like a giant powerful pose which was
good. But
>> I know I do need a ras because like I
don't know he god for adid there's a bad
game but that clip will be everywhere.
[laughter]
>> It's an incentive to play well.
>> Game too actually.
>> No never mind that coach is going to be
[laughter] regardless.
>> It'll be there man. It's one guy
>> for you being able to, you know, come in
and you hear the head coach of the
Cleveland Browns, Todd Mugan, say that's
our left tackle,
>> you know, and that is the position you
just texted him, Joe Thomas occupied for
the Cleveland Browns, right?
>> That's the that's the spot on the
offensive line. When you hear your coach
have that kind of confidence, we drafted
you. They could have picked any lineman
in this draft. They said, "We want
Spencer Fono on our team to be our left
tackle." What does that mean to you? And
how excited are you to get back over
there and uh on the blind side? I am I
am so excited. I mean um yeah, in
college I I really I still now I've
never cared where I played.
>> Yeah.
>> I mean sure if they wanted to stick me
in the center I would do it.
>> They want to put me a receiver I would
do it but [laughter] like I don't know
to be believed in that much to play a
position that pivotal.
>> Um it's it it means a lot to me and I'm
not one that likes to let people down.
>> So you were talking uh our good friend
Chris Rose who does works for NFL
Network. He does the preseason TV for
the Browns. was at the combine and you
were doing some of the center drills and
I guess he stopped you in the hall and
said what are you going to catch punts
next and you [laughter] and you told
you're like I'll do what whatever they
asked me to do
>> cuz they were just like hey any
nonenters want to get snaps in and I was
like you know what the the first O line
position I played cuz I was a running
back growing up
>> really
>> and then I was finally too heavy in
eighth grade and then uh my dad was my
coach and he put me in at center um it
was the only year it was the only year I
played center but Um, yeah. So there
anyone that that thinks they can snap,
go ahead. So I was, okay, I'll do it.
>> That's [laughter] an unbelievable story.
I can imagine seventh graders trying to
tackle.
>> Yeah, I was saying Do you remember how
many touchdowns you scored in seventh
grade?
>> I did have a lot of touchdowns.
[laughter]
>> Yeah,
>> I did have a lot.
>> I think you might had more touchdowns
than people who legitimately tackled you
in the field of play.
>> Oh my gosh. I was It was I was like And
the whole time it's not like I was some
finesse running back and I was just
[laughter]
>> I was running into people.
>> Yeah,
>> I was just running into people. when
when you are a tackle and and I don't
know this or not, we're just getting to
know each other here, but being a a
student of the game and we were talking
about Joe and one thing that Joe is so
willing to do and he's done it before
with our offensive lineman who we've
drafted is he is available as much as
you want and you could make an argument
that he's the greatest left tackle in
the history of the game. He's certainly
in the all-time game in the history of
the sport. That type of resource, what
does that mean to you? What do you know
about his career? What do you know about
kind of the legacy of that position
here? Yeah, I mean I I just glazing Joe
Thomas. I mean like I I personally
believe that he is the greatest lineman
of all time. I mean um I know about like
key just like growing up and seeing the
stat how he played and didn't miss a
snap for 10 years.
>> Yeah. No, I I feel like I don't know
just you as a lineman and you know how
like gritty it is and you know how um
>> I don't know how easy it is to get hurt
for certain things and the fact that you
played 10 years in the National Football
League and you don't miss a snap. I feel
like that not only and then not only not
don't miss a snap but you play as well
as he did.
>> Um I think it doesn't it doesn't only
speak to um how good of a player he was
and but his freaking character
>> he wanted to be there for his team.
>> That's insane. That's insane. So
>> 10,363
is that I think I have that that right.
Consecutive
>> snaps. If I was able to learn from him,
I I would I would love to become his
shadow.
>> Well, one of the things that's cool is
that, you know, he wasn't one of those,
you know, you have some mountain tackles
where they're just giant strong. He was
a master technician. He was so athletic.
I mean, you'll watch him do onelegged
kicksteps and he can go down the field
faster than I can run at my old age
these days. You're an athletic guy. so
athletic that's got jumps off of the
tape and that's one of the things that
has allowed you to always be in
position. So I think it's kind of a
natural synergy there.
>> True. Yeah. I mean I would love to just
learn from him and um yeah like I said
before just be his shadow.
>> Can I ask you this in the combine and
going through this process? Right. Is
this the only time in your life that
somebody was like there's a part of you
that might be too small? I mean where we
get oh 32 in and 78. Not quite 33. like
it was crazy.
>> You've been the biggest guy probably
around for your whole life.
>> Yeah. Yeah. It's funny. Yeah, that that
actually is pretty hilarious. But then
yeah, it's like suddenly I'm tiny
compared to other guys. Like I still
feel like I'm a pretty big dude.
>> You are a big dude. I can verify that.
Yes, you are a big dude. It's just one
of those strange things that we talk
about all the time. I remember when
Jared Goff came out and they said, "No,
his hands are too small." Nobody's
mentioned his hands since he's gotten in
the NFL. That's one of those things
that's talked about for a very finite
window and then you go play and and you
carry on with it. What what do you uh
when you are the first player for any
team's draft,
>> there's a responsibility to it. Uh
there's a responsibility to yourself,
your family, the organization, the city,
the fans. Um it's it's a lot. It can be
a lot. How has your life prepared you
for this moment now?
>> That was a fire question. Oh my gosh.
Boy. Oh my.
>> You're going to do just fine, buddy.
>> He's a big B broadcaster, folks. He's
going to do just fine. You're going to
love him. Yes. Um,
I I I I feel like I've been
I feel like I have been um
what's the word? crafted for this kind
of moment or for this kind of
responsibility.
>> Um,
>> team captain in college.
>> Yes, sir. And I feel I've always I've
been given that kind of leadership role
all growing up. Um, and I know that I
this first year I'm ready to just be a a
rookie and to just um um follow in the
guys that have been here their
footsteps. But I don't know, like I I'm
I I just I know what I want to do. I
know my goals. Um to me, this is like
getting when I got to Utah for my
freshman year in college. Um how I was
able to start as a true freshman. Um and
I just know I'll do whatever it takes. I
I'll do whatever it takes.
>> Yeah. I mean, one of the things that
both Andrew Barry said and Todd Mon said
to you, but then also said in here to to
me last night on the radio broadcast was
that they think you are a culture
setter. And you know, one
[clears throat] of the things that Joe
Thomas and even Joel Baton, we've had
some great offensive linemen here, they
say at times it can be hard for an
offensive lineman to be a culture
setter. So, the way that Joe went about
it was
>> taking every rep seriously, playing
10,363 snaps in a row. You know, kind of
what's your approach to leadership from
a position that doesn't touch the ball,
right? So, it's a little different that
way. Uh, I think it's all about energy,
right? It's it's about energy. And then
not only that, with all with the O line,
>> everybody knows that nothing starts
without the O line. And so, um,
>> set the tone.
>> Yes. And when you we set the tone and
when we were moving, um, when we're
moving dudes off the ball, I feel like
that just sets the energy for everybody.
I mean, at every any level I played at,
um, if we sucked, the team, like the
offense sucked,
>> but if we were killing it, it gave the
opportunity for everybody else to do the
same. So, I feel like that's that's
where my role will come in as being a
culture setter, which is is just doing
my job and bring energy.
>> Yeah. Quinton Judkins here, Dylan
Samson, some darn good productive
running backs as well. Is that Do you
like run blocking more than pass
blocking?
>> Yeah.
>> Because you like just being getting
physical, getting violent.
>> Yeah. But I mean, shoot, everything's
part of the job. So, I enjoy all of
[laughter] it. Yeah.
>> You're I mean, I know you got to run. I
just sell you this, buddy. Uh and I
would tell the audience this. Your your
personality is infectious. your culture
tornado and you could feel it when you
got into the building today. You felt it
in the press conference. You feel it in
here right now. This this fan base is
going to eat you up, buddy. And it's
going to you're going to feed off each
other in a really positive way. Welcome
to Cleveland, pal.
>> Let's go. Thank you so much. Thank you.
>> Come on, man. First round pick. Spenco
in studio with